LONPUR
Good morning.
Tell me something swamiji.
You're such a good
detective and yet
you don't charge money
after solving the case
nor do you take
credit for it in the news.
So you want me to charge
money to find goats? No, no, no...
That would be against
mine and the goat's pride.
Besides, taaka maati, maati taaka.
Taka taki maka maki? What?
Money is like sand.
Ramakrishna Paramahansa.
Don't you know that
Mr. Ashram visitor?
-Good morning.
-Good morning Mrs. H.
Did you hear?
Swamiji has proclaimed
today that money is like sand.
So I think we should start paying
our rent to Mrs. H with a box of sand.
I will throw that sand
back in your faces.
No need for tension Henry.
He has a pension.
-A pension isn't enough these days.
-You also have a permanent job.
-You are my assistant.
-Hello?
Not assistant okay. Partner.
I thought that we should start
our own detective agency.
To solve cases and make money.
-That's a great idea.
-No, no, no.
See Mrs. H?
He might be a talented man
but he is also very selfish.
No, no, no.
If not about yourself,
at least think about others.
-No. No.
-Think about Mrs. H.
-I am all alone Shekhar.
-Yeah.
Your rent would really
help me, you know?
Yeah, she needs the money.
What do you say?
One...
One week. We can try it
out for one week.
Yes!
-Yes, but I will handle the money.
-Absolutely.
What should we name our agency?
Saini and Home detective agency?
How about, 'Saini, Home
and Henry associates'?
Oh! Then why don't
we include Pintu also?
Saini, Home, Henry and Pintu
will become... SHHP...
I think it's Henry and Saini...
That will be...
Well done!
I have been seeing
ghosts for the last few days.
That is not a ghost,
that is Jayavrat.
She received a family gold chain
on her 18th birthday from dad.
But when we opened the
box to wear it for the wedding
last night the chain was missing.
Mr. Shekhar I wrote a story last
night that was 15 pages long.
When I woke up in the morning
three pages were missing.
Don't worry, he is very good
at ending the story.
Don't worry, he knows how to
talk to ghosts.
You just need to pay the fees.
100 rupees.
50 rupees only.
You just need to pay us.
No... he is a student.
-Oh, are you a student?
-Yes.
Then you get a 50% student discount.
50 rupees only.
100 rupees only.
He is such a bad doctor!
He is asking for money from a cop?
The cops should...
No...
Well, okay...
Goswami...
I don't feel good.
Why?
Because Das isn't here.
He always sets a good mood.
He must be attending a wedding.
Since he is unable to get
married himself.
Hey, that is a good thing.
Otherwise he would go from
Das to sad.
-Just like us.
-Should I tell your wife that?
Hey, Goswami...
-Here. You eat.
-Sad huh?
From Chatterjee to sad.
From Das to sad.
Good morning.
Good morning Das.
Good morning Das?
Das?
Good morning.
Mr. Shekhar, I was sitting in
my store like I generally do...
And looking at matrimonial ads.
-What?
-Everyone in Lonpur knows
what you do in your shop.
Which ads you cross out and which
ones you circle. Please go on.
What else can I do Shekhar?
A good girl is like the view
from Kangchenjunga.
It's not easy.
You need to work hard for it.
So, did you find a girl Mr. Das?
I found a flyer.
I found a flyer in the newspaper
that had an ad
looking for a groom.
It said that the girl
has four conditions.
Interesting.
The boy that she wants...
You mean 'man', right?
A man above the age of 40.
A Bengali whose
surname starts with D...
and who runs their own business.
So I fulfilled all four of them.
I even met the girl's father,
Shottendra Sanyal.
He was a very good man.
A complete gentleman.
He even said -
I can't believe my luck.
You have all four qualities.
You would be absolutely perfect
for my daughter Menaka.
Absolutely perfect.
Thank you sir. Er...
Papa.
It looks like we will all have to
prepare for your welcome
son-in-law.
But there is one small problem.
My daughter is a forest officer.
She wants a life partner
who would be willing to
move out of the city
and live in a forest if necessary.
Of course I am
willing to do that.
We will see.
If you live in this jungle
and survive for 30 days
then on the 31st day you
can marry Menaka.
Live in a jungle for a month?
All alone?
I had to prove that I could
live in the jungle for 30 days.
For Menaka I had to become
the sage Vishvamitra.
I sacrificed my house, my shop
and everything for her.
Dad...
I mean, Mr. Sanyal...
would give me a task every day
and I would put all my effort into
completing the task.
DAY ONE
DAY SIX
Menaka's condition was to
fulfill every single day's task
if I skipped even a single task
then I would have to restart.
DAY THIRTEEN
But Mr. Sanyal
didn't show up today.
DAY TWENTY
I waited for a very long time.
When I enquired from the
forest rangers, they told me…
That there is no forest
officer named Menaka.
And nobody knows anyone by the
name of Sanyal either.
Ouch.
Shekhar, I have
completed 20 days out of 30.
There are only 10 days remaining.
If I stop now...
I will turn into a widow
before I even got married.
-Widower.
-What?
Not a 'widow', you would be a
'widower' since you are a man.
So you want me to find Sanyal?
That's right.
Okay then Mr. Das.
1,000 rupees.
500 right now and 500 with
the wedding sweets?
Doctor, my shop has been shut
for the last 20 days.
I don't have any money.
That's fine, you can give me
whatever you have.
-You can give it later.
-Shekhar!
-How could you do that?
-He doesn't have any money.
-This is my department.
-This is my company.
It's our company.
Then it's time to shut down.
Which jungle is it?
Brother, Das and Bhootnath
kyalakeli korche.
-Kala Koli?
-They are fighting! Hurry up!
It’s not about my
house or your house,
why would you do an
illegal construction...
Who says it's illegal? This
is the wall of my house,
I did this construction.
My father was alive when it was built.
It’s not about your
house or my house,
-our houses are facing each other...
-This wall was created by my father!
Did you think I wouldn't
notice, you thief!
How am I the thief? The wall
is exactly where the line was!
You liar! You are a cheat!
-Break the wall. Do it!
-I won't.
Then I will break you.
Hey, hey, why are you fighting?
You might get hurt.
I am not afraid of getting hurt.
I have a balm in my shop.
Crocodile brand balm.
-I will...
-Hey!
You guys don't know
how to use your fists.
Use your words and talk it out.
Where are you going?
To eat lunch.
Who is that?
This is Das' Menaka.
Das and her?
She could be miss universe.
A desperate man like Das
was bound to fall for it.
Yes, because everyone in Lonpur
knows
that Das spends his days
looking at matrimonials.
Show me your hand.
-Why?
-Just do it.
-What is this?
-The key to the company.
It's time to open up again.
-Where are you going?
-What?
Didn't you just say we
we are going out for lunch?
Partner!
So, we already know what Das wants.
Now tell me what Sanyal wants.
You know what I think?
I think Sanyal was
sent by Bhoothnath.
Das' cousin brother.
Bhootnath and Das have been
enemies for a very long time
because of a dispute
over land they inherited.
Bhoothnath must have sent Sanyal
to send Das into the jungle
while Bhootnath broke the
old wall and built a new one.
Game. Set. Match.
Chamionship partner.
Wow, such a terrible deduction.
Wait, wait a minute.
Why? What was so bad about it?
There is a suspect and a motive
and I even investigated it myself.
I saw them fighting about the
land and the position of the wall.
-Really?
-Yes!
So, how long does it take
to build a wall?
To build... It probably
takes two days.
And for how long was
Mr. Das sent to the jungle?
For 30 days.
Huh?
Afternoon Henry.
Good afternoon.
-Good afternoon Mrs. H.
-Good afternoon.
Two specials for us please.
Namaste sister-in-law.
Laltoo!
Hello.
So... I see you're eating
Kosha Mangsho.
Of course, a Sunday holiday
is all about enjoying
time and Mangsho with my family.
A cop taking a holiday means
they have solved all their cases.
-Just like our Jayavrat.
-Hey!
- Conceited man.
-Good joke. Good joke.
So, what case are you guys
working on right now?
Das. Abhirup Das.
No way. That good-for-nothing Das?
Shekhar, will you work
for anyone who pays you?
You have lost your soul
to capitalism my friend.
He is the capitalist. Not me.
What do you mean capitalist?
Our Karl Marx from Lonpur over here
is helping the poor guy for free?
Who is a poor guy?
That guy is a complete...
Good boy.
Don't move your hands.
Don't try to listen.
He is a complete bastard.
Do you know Urmila from
the chemist shop?
He was desperate
to get married to her.
But he caused a huge scene.
She complained against him
and I beat him
away with my stick.
But he still didn't stop.
Do you know what he did?
He cut his wrists and wrote
the girl a letter with his blood.
And he didn't even get a
government stamp.
Poor guy? Bloody bastard.
My son...
So partner?
Urmila who works
at the medical store.
Let's go meet her.
-Let's have lunch first.
-You can eat later.
But...
No, just go. Go.
You have to go.
Both of you.
-Come on!
-Okay...
-Give this to Abra uncle.
-Okay sir.
Oh and take this too.
Give it to Abra uncle. Quickly.
Oh Shekhar!
And Jayabroto is with you too?
-Jayavrat.
-Exactly.
Where is Urmila?
I need to speak to her.
Should I call her? Urmila!
Come out.
He...
Hey wait! Listen. Listen.
Please listen.
-Just listen to me.
-Please.
Please stop following me.
I do not want to marry you.
-Huh?
-What?
Marry? You?
Never.
-So you don't want to get married?
-No, not at all.
Then why do you keep sending Mrs. H
to my house with a proposal?
Last time she brought
flowers and sweets.
You are a weird man.
Acting innocent now.
You like me but you can't
even say it to my face?
Sorry.
-Look, I don't want to get married.
-I see.
And... you...
sorry but I definitely don't
want to get married to you.
If you don't want to get married
then why are you following me?
-Because--
-Oh so it's for a case again!
-Again?
-That's right. Again.
Last time Inspector Laha was here
and he informed me that I am
the 'U' Killer's girlfriend.
'U' for Urmila.
That is what he said.
First Das, and then Laha
and now you two.
Have all the men in
town lost their minds?
Is that why you wanted
revenge against Das?
No, no, listen.
I don't even want to look
at Das to get revenge.
-Are you guys done?
-Yes.
-Can I leave?
-Yes. Sorry...
Good.
"Is that why you wanted
revenge against Das?"
You have the subtlety
of a hammer my friend.
What? Me? What about you?
What you said to her?
Is she that bad?
I don't want to get married!
Why don't you and Henry
start a matrimonial together?
Both of you are pushing
me to get married!
You shouldn't be so
adamant about everything...
Urmila was right.
About what? That she is very pretty?
Should I tell Mrs. H
to talk to her again?
Oh! Joke?
Why are you taking out your
anger at Urmila's words on me?
Do one thing, meet Das and
find out how many people
have a problem with him.
I am sure that must
be a very long list.
Every single girl in
Lonpur must be on it.
Hey, don't speculate.
Just go and do your job.
I need to speak to Henry.
Yes partner!
Oh Henry.
Stop going to girls with
my marriage proposal!
-But she is beautiful, right?
-I don't care Henry!
So do you want to be like Das?
When you're old we will find you
with a newspaper in your hand.
You too! Duffers! Both of you.
Big duffers.
What happened now?
What?
What are you doing?
Nothing. What did Das say?
That guy is still stuck on
Bhootnath and Menaka.
He says he has no
enemies in Lonpur.
And everyone in the
city knows everyone else.
So Sanyal is definitely
not from around here.
But now the question is,
which person from Lonpur
gave Sanyal Das' details?
Do you know how many drunkards
we have who gossip all day?
Buggers like Chatterjee
do that all day!
What?
Shekhar! Shekhar! Ah!
Shekhar!
What the hell?
I sent you to Das didn't I?
Where else did you go?
I just came from his shop.
Hey Shekhar!
Shekhar!
What happened Shekhar?
Where are you going?
Shekhar! I am heading back.
Hey!
How is this open?
Let's go and inform Das.
What are you doing?
What? Me?
Do I look like a wrestler to you?
Come on soldier. You can do it.
Come on.
It's not that easy
to remove a grill...
Hey... Shekhar,
this is trespassing.
What are we doing here?
Tell me?
Interesting.
Did we break in
here to look at art?
Let's take this with us.
Have you lost your mind?
We are already here anyway.
Let's take it with us.
Help? Help?
Please, come on help.
-Shekhar...
-Come on, lift.
What?
What is this?
[in Bengali] On the lap of the
banyan tree, go towards the South,
then towards North east,
I give you the directions!
This is a long tunnel.
What?
Everyone should have
an assistant like you.
Hey! I am not your assistant,
I am your partner okay?
Shekhar where are you going? Hey.
I feel like sneezing.
What if I fall?
You will stop sneezing for good.
Oh God... where are we?
This is the vault of
Lonpur Co-operative Bank.
A truck of cash
arrives every Saturday.
That is how they must have
planned their robbery.
Commit the robbery on Saturday night
since the bank will be closed on Sunday.
By the time the bank opens on
Monday morning they would be gone.
Right? Shekhar?
Shekhar, this robbery was carried
out on the weekend on purpose.
-Cellotape.
-Cellotape?
Banatul Industrial Detergent.
You won't find it
anywhere near Lonpur.
Ladies and gentlemen, now with
extra foam and hydrogen peroxide.
-Hydrogen peroxide?
-Ding!
Did you pass by Das' shop
day before yesterday?
Yes, I passed by
this place on my walk.
I could smell something too.
Like something was burning!
Nitro... Nitroglycerin.
Nitroglycerin.
It is used in bombs.
And as soon as you come in
contact with it
a person will start sneezing.
-Shekhar!
-Hey, are you crazy?
He is a genius!
Hey! What are you doing?
-Hey!
-Don't worry I will take care of it.
What are you doing Shekhar?
I was just calling you a genius.
Now do you know who did it?
Just by looking at the masks?
You just called me a genius, right?
Why did you call me here?
-To tell you a story.
-What do you mean?
I mean, this story has
drama, emotion, romance
and even action.
But it is still a crime.
You see, a few months ago some
people got together and made a plan.
A plan to loot the bank.
But why are you telling us this?
Because there is a list...
Laha! File!
This is a list of all the loans that
were rejected in the last six months.
Bhootnath!
Goswami.
Chatterjee.
Miss Urmila.
'U' for Urmila.
Yes, 'U' for Urmila and
'C' for Chatterjee.
You see what I see?
Yes...
They had a plan to build
a home away from Lonpur.
They needed a loan and
it was rejected.
Primary applicant Chatterjee.
Co-applicant Urmila.
And when the bank refused they
decided to loot the bank itself.
Wait... wait... wait a second sir.
The two of us are
in a relationship...
everyone knows that by now.
I accept it, but I didn't
loot any banks!
I didn't even know about the
secret tunnel under Das' shop.
You didn't know but she knew.
Knew what?
I don't know anything.
You sign on the receipts at
your medical shop don't you?
Yes.
You know the register at
the Lonpur library?
It has your sign.
You borrowed the book with the
blueprint didn't you?
Which had a map to the tunnel
below the bank, right?
I... cross-checked that signature
and it was a perfect match.
Just like you and Chatterjee.
Then he must have done that.
Yes, to get me out of the way.
Sir, you see!
She is talking too much!
Talking too much? You stole the
money to go back to your wife, right?
-You bloody cheater.
-Hey! Not a cheater.
No cheater.
Cheater is an American distortion.
The word is cheat.
British English?
Do you work for the BBC?
Oh no, thank you very much.
-You are a cheat! Yes, you are.
-I am a cheat?
She is a selfish woman. I was about
to leave my caring wife for you!
-Caring wife? You just remembered that?
-Quiet. Calm down.
Shut up!
Both of you shut up.
Ananto!
Ananto! Hey!
Listen, head to their
houses right now...
-Sir--
-Shut up! Shut up. Go to their house...
...search their house, they must
be hiding the money there.
Find the money, count
it and bring it back here.
Hey, Ananto.
36 Lakhs 57 thousand and 19 rupees.
And 75 paise.
Go. Hurry up.
-You stole so much money?
-Hey, hey, enough. Shut up!
Look, the honeymoon
hotel is ready for you guys.
-Tell me if you want to go in.
-Take your wife with you!
-Sir--
-Shut up!
Look, the two of you can leave.
But... But...
the investigation is
not over yet, okay?
Don't talk to anyone about this.
And if you do, he won't spare you.
-Sir...
-Shut up!
Hello? Hello Shekhar? We found
the real thieves and the money.
Why are you so excited?
Did you think I could be wrong?
Fine Shekhar. We found
the money and the thieves
just like you said, okay?
Hello Mr. Sanyal.
Mr. Goswami.
It was a good plan but
you made a mistake.
36 Lakhs 57 thousand and 19 rupees.
And 75 paise.
I said the wrong amount
at the police station Mr. Goswami.
So that you could take
us to uncle Abra.
PAHARPUR 2 KMs
-What did you do uncle?
-What?
You said that you found
28 lakh 95 thousand rupees.
But 36 lakhs are
missing from the bank!
Here! Take this 8 lakhs and this
36 lakhs and count it yourself!
Obviously I will count it myself.
When did you get this idea?
I came to Lonpur to search for
something in Mangal Ashram.
As Mrs. H calls it... Lady Luck.
She is the one who
saved Bablu's life today.
Otherwise...
In real life I don't have a
lady nor do I have any luck.
Das... don't be sad.
You will find her soon enough.
When?
I am tired of looking.
Mr. Das,
if not today, you will find her
tomorrow - your dream girl.
Very soon you will have a lady
and luck on your side.
Really?
You are my closest friend Goswami.
After the landlords only you
could make use of that tunnel.
Urmila's sign...
the one you made in the register.
It was easy.
She used to sign on the bills
and I just copied it.
When it was time
to execute the plan
your uncle Abra entered the scene.
Nobody in Lonpur knew him
and there were no police records.
Smart move.
But you made a mistake.
You made him a guarantor
on your loan application.
He turned into Sanyal to turn
Das into Devdas.
The poor guy didn't get
his Chandramukhi,
nor Paro, nor Menaka.
Bomb.
You made it well.
Silent. Powerful.
But you made a mistake there too.
The smell of nitroglycerin.
If I hadn't smelt it I could
never have found out.
I should have used ammonium nitrate
that was my mistake.
Ammonium perchlorate.
Why don't you make
the bomb next time?
Seriously?
We can share the money.
No... I mean...
my company does want me to hit
certain money targets though.
Well, anyway...
it's clear how and why this
robbery took place.
Is it clear?
Yes, I mean... anyone could have
signed there right?
So how did these two...
Medrol.
Give this to Abra uncle.
Medrol means that uncle has COPD.
Hey, do that later.
Let him cough. He has COPD.
Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease.
Chronic... Pul...
Yes, exactly.
Laha, you remember the masks
we found in the trash?
One of those masks had an
extra layer of cloth.
You see, digging
a tunnel with bombs
causes a lot of sand
and dirt to float around.
That would have triggered his COPD.
This was for uncle's protection.
Uncle?
You see your nephew here?
He is very cunning.
He was sitting in Khasha Blanca
when the crime was committed.
He has an alibi.
Far away from the crime scene.
Catching him without the loot
was pointless.
That is why we caught
him here red-handed.
Thank you Shekhar.
This is a very big case that has been
added to Lonpur Police Station's ledger.
Yes, but this time a
thank you won't be enough.
Okay, well would you like
rasgullas or mutton?
No way. There is a
big reward and a credit.
We want a share in both.
But Shekhar... what
about our arrangement?
That is over now.
This will now be my department.
Shekhar?
Don't talk to me.
-What?
-Discuss it with the corporate guy.
Doctor?
Yes, this...
this is your certificate.
And cash?
Yes, here... 15,000...
Two years of rent,
the bulb you broke
and all other damages.
We are ready to
move on to stage two.